So, far we've built a quantity picker.
수량 picker를 만들었어요.
&gt;&gt; Right. And
&gt;&gt; 맞아요.
the next place to go in the app is the price.
앱에서 도달할 다음 장소는 가격이죠.
&gt;&gt; Yes.
&gt;&gt; 네. 가격이죠.
So, price is an integer so far, but we want to move beyond that and
가격은 정수[interger]지만 우리는 그 이상이 되길 바라므로
use strings.
문자열[string]을 사용할게요.
&gt;&gt; You mean, this type of string?
&gt;&gt; 이런 종류의 끈이요?
&gt;&gt; No I mean like this type of string.
&gt;&gt; 아뇨, 이런 종류의 문자열이요.
&gt;&gt; Huh.
&gt;&gt; 아.
&gt;&gt; So a string is just a sequence of characters.
&gt;&gt; 문자열은 단지 문자의 나열입니다.
&gt;&gt; So wait. How does this work with the price then?
&gt;&gt; 잠시만요, 그게 어떻게 가격과 작용하죠?
&gt;&gt; So we're going to change the screen so that it says total.
&gt;&gt; 우리는 화면을 바꿔 총액을 보여주게 할 겁니다.
And then $15.
그럼 15달러가 되죠.
So it's not just a number, now it has some text with it as well.
이건 그냥 숫자가 아니라 텍스트도 포함하고 있죠.
&gt;&gt; Numbers and text.
&gt;&gt; 숫자와 문자네요.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Isn't that awesome?
&gt;&gt; 네, 멋지지 않아요?
This is from the party that you may or may not have [LAUGH] been invited to.
이건 당신이 초대 받았을 수도 있고 아닐 수도 있는 파티에서 왔어요.
Over the next few videos we'll talk about using strings
다음 비디오에서 우리는 Just Java 앱에서
in our Just Java app.
문자열을 사용하는 것을 다룰 겁니다.
Specifically, we'll learn how to create and update string variables in the app.
특히, 앱에서 문자열 변수를 만들고 업데이트하는 법을 배울거예요.
Then we'll change the app so that under the price header it says total, $15 or
그리고 앱을 바꿔서 price 제목 아래에 총액이 $15나
whatever the price is based on the quantity ordered.
주문 수량에 따른 가격으로 표시되게 할 것입니다.
We'll also show the text,
또한 텍스트를 보여줄 겁니다.
Thank you, because we're excited about having any customers at all.
고마워요, 손님을 갖게 되는 게 꽤 흥분되네요.
You might be wondering why don't we just put all of this text
XML 레이아웃 안에 모든 텍스트 뷰를 넣지 않는지
inside the XML layout?
궁금하실 겁니다.
Well, we could, but the problem is that the quantity can change and
할 수는 있지만, 문제는 수량은 변할 수 있으며
when we hit the order button, we want the price to be updated here.
주문 버튼을 눌렀을 때, 가격이 갱신되길 원한다는 점입니다.
So this text needs to accurately reflect the price based on the quantity.
이 텍스트는 수량에 기반해 정확한 가격을 반영해야 합니다.
By using a string variable, we can change the value of the text while
문자열 변수를 사용하면, XML 레이아웃 전체에
the app is running without having to hard code it into the whole XML layout.
어렵게 코딩할 필요 없이 앱이 작동할 때
Here's an example from real apps that you may recognize.
당신이 알아볼 실제 앱에서 가져온 예입니다.
When you receive an incoming call you see the person's name at the top
수신 전화를 받을 때 화면의 상단에 사람의 이름을 봅니다.
We can't put this name directly into the XML layout
우리는 이 이름을 XML 레이아웃에 직접 넣을 수 없습니다.
because it will change depending on who calls you, unless all your family and
모든 가족과 친구들 이름이 Britta Holt가 아닌 이상
The best thing to do is to store this name in a string variable.
최선은 이름을 문자열 변수에 저장하는 것입니다.
That way you can update it depending on who calls you.
이 방법으로 당신은 전화한 사람에 따라 업데이트할 수 있죠.
Then when we show this screen we can just display the latest name
이 화면을 보여줄 때 그 변수에 저장된
that is stored in that variable.
최근 이름을 보여주면 되죠.
In the News and Weather app, we see a list of the top news stories.
뉴스, 날씨 앱에서 상위 뉴스 목록을 봅니다.
When we build the XML layout, we can't just specifically hard code
XML 레이아웃을 만들 때 XML 레이아웃 안에
these specific news stories into the XML layout.
그 특정 뉴스를 힘들게 입력하지 않아요.
As much as I love reading about the Winter Olympics,
저는 동계 올림픽에 대해 읽는 걸 좋아하지만
I do want to see other news articles as well.
다른 뉴스들도 보고 싶어요.
So we can store the information for each news story,
각 뉴스 이야기에 대한 기사 제목 같은 정보를
For the next task I'm going to provide you with some code and
다음 작업에서 코드를 제공하겠습니다.
I'm going to have you make those changes in your app.
당신 앱에서 변화를 주세요.
Then you'll run the app and then observe what happens.
앱을 실행해서 무엇이 발생하는지 관찰하세요.
I'll ask you some questions to see if you can try to figure out
당신이 무엇이 발생하는지 알아냈는지 보기 위해
what's going on.
질문을 하겠습니다.
The first change is to modify the submitOrder method.
첫 변화는 submitOrder 메소드를 수정하는 겁니다.
You can remove the code that's already in between the opening and
열고 닫는 중괄호 사이에 있는 코드를 지울 수 있어요.
closing braces and then replace it with these two lines of code.
그리고 이 두 줄의 코드로 대체하세요.
Adding this code will give you an error, so I want you to also
이 코드를 넣으면 에러가 생길텐데 저는 여러분이 displayMessage
add the displayMessage method, which we've provided in the instructor notes.
메소드도 추가하길 바라요. 이는 instructor notes에 있어요.
In the instructor notes, you'll find this Gist of code.
instructor notes에 이 코드 gist를 찾을 수 있어요.
Go ahead and select the whole thing,
진행하여 코멘트부터
from the comment all the way to the last closing brace.
마지막 닫는 중괄호까지 모든 것을 선택하세요.
You can treat this method like a black box,
이 메소드를 블랙 박스처럼 다룰 수 있어요.
you don't have to worry about what's going on Inside of the method, you just
이 메소드 안에서 무슨 일이 일어날까 걱정하지 마세요.
need to know that you want to add it to the MainActivity so that you can use it.
그저 이것을 사용하기 위해서 Main Activity에 추가하는 것입니다.
Back in Android Studio,
Android Studio로 돌아와서,
in the MainActivity.java file, I'm going to paste in this new method.
MainActivity.java 파일에 이 새 메소드를 추가할 겁니다.
I can paste it anywhere in the MainActivity, but
MainActivity 안에 어디든 이것을 붙여넣을 수 있죠.
I'm just going to put it right after the displayPrice method.
이것을 displayPrice 메소드 바로 다음에 놓을게요.
And I'm going to put it after
displayPrice 메소드의
the closing brace of the displayPrice method.
닫는 중괄호 다음에 이걸 놓겠습니다.
Notice that it's also inside of the closing brace of the MainActivity.
이것은 MainActivity의 닫는 중괄호 안에 있습니다.
The MainActivity has an opening brace right here,
MainActivity는 바로 여기에 여는 중괄호를 갖고 있죠.
and everything inside of it is contained within the MainActivity.
여기 안의 모든 것은 Main Activity 안에 있습니다.
And then you have a closing brace for the MainActivity here.
여기에 MainActivity를 위한 닫는 중괄호가 있죠.
Once we've added the displayMessage method in,
displayMessage 메소드를 추가하면
we can now modify the submitOrder method.
이제 submitOrder 메소드를 수정할 수 있습니다.
I'm going to erase the code that we already have inside
submitOrder 메소드 안에 가지고 있던 코드를
the submitOrder method.
지우겠습니다.
Then according to the quiz image, I'm going to add the new code here.
퀴즈 이미지에 맞게 여기 새 코드를 추가합니다.
Intentionally I'm not giving you too many details on what I just did.
의도적으로 제가 방금 한 것에 대해 자세한 정보를 드리지 않고 있어요.
I want you to try it out in your version of the app, run it, and
여러분이 여러분 앱에서 시도해보고, 실행해보고
see what happens.
어떻게 되는지 보길 바라요.
After that I want you to answer these questions.
그 후에 이 질문들에 답해주세요.
What happens when you click on the order button in the app now?
이제 앱의 주문 버튼을 누르면 무슨 일이 일어나죠?
If you take a look at the submit order code more closely,
이 주문 제출 코드를 자세히 보시면
we actually created a string variable.
사실 문자열 변수를 만들었어요.
Even though we haven't gone over the code for string variables, I want you to
우리가 문자열 변수를 위한 코드를 쓰진 않았지만
make your best guess as to, what do you think the variable name is?
그랬듯이 최선의 추측을 해보세요. 이 변수의 이름이 무엇인 것 같나요?
And what do you think the variable value is?
이 변수 값이 무엇이라고 생각하나요?
When you are done go ahead and continue.
다 되었으면 계속하세요.